+19024480058 | **E**: juni.roy5@gmail.com Halifax, NS B3J2K9

https://oysheesaharoy.com/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have completed my Master in Computer Science from Dalhousie University. My area of specialization is Human Computer Interaction.

I have also worked as a Student Data Analyst at Dalhousie University. I have 3.5 years of experience of working as a Senior Systems Engineer at Infosys Limited.

SKILLS

- Python, Java, BrightScript, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, shell scripting
- MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL
- Tableau, Mendix, GitHub, Jira,
 Mantis, Bitbucket, Putty
- Anaconda Distributions, Eclipse, Pycharm, Sublime text, Google Colab, Microsoft Visual Studio, Notepad++
- Data Science and Machine Learning Algorithms
- Qualitative and Quantitative data analysis
- Conducting user studies
- Designing prototypes for applications
- Design and build static and dynamic website
- Designing using Inkscape

PUBLICATION \bigcirc

Oyshee Saha Roy and James Blustein, "Protocol to build a Framework for Designing an Interactive Tool for Art Gallery Visitors"," HUMAN'19: 2nd International Workshop on Human Factors in Hypertext Proceedings", 2019, Hof, Germany.

WORK HISTORY

STUDENT ANALYST

02/2019 to 08/2019

Dalhousie University | Halifax, NS

- Participated in requirements meetings and data mapping sessions to understand business needs
- Designed and developed schema data models
- Fetching JSON data from RESTful APIs. The fetched data were cleaned and stored in tables in PostgreSQL
- The collected data was further processed using Fuzzy matching
- Helped solve diverse program problems with in-depth analysis
- Analyzed data were visualized using matplotlib, plotly, and Dash apps
- Updated organizational subsystems to improve and streamline data collection

RESIDENCE ASSISTANT AND GUEST SIGN-IN STAFF 09/2018 to 04/2019

Dalhousie University | Halifax, NS

• Key responsibilities include interacting with students, hosting residence

- events and programming, role-modeling, peer counselling and ensuring students' rights to a positive living- learning environment are respected
- Responsible for working with Residence Life Staff and Dal Security to promote a safe and inclusive living environment

SENIOR SYSTEMS ENGINEER

08/2014 to 12/2017

Infosys Limited | Trivandrum, India

- I have worked in Media, Logistics and Retail domain
- Experience in front-end scripting of Roku boxes
- Experience in development and maintenance of Mendix applications
- Experience in working on Loyalty based projects and development of POS systems
- Worked closely with clients, and team members to determine planning, implementation and integration of system-oriented projects
- Participated in all phases of system development life cycle, from requirements analysis through system implementation
- Created flowcharts, diagrams and other documentation

EDUCATION \bigcirc

Master of Computer Science | Computer Science Dalhousie University, Halifax

10/2014

Thesis: Framework to Guide Designing of Interactive Tools for Art Galleries
The thesis proposes a framework which will help in designing and building of
interactive tools for art galleries. The research started with the background
analysis of all the factors that influence the planning of an exhibit/show at an art
gallery. One to-one interviews were conducted with the art curators from
different art galleries in Nova Scotia, Canada. The Maud Lewis exhibit (present
at Art Gallery of Nova Scotia, Halifax) has been used to test the framework.

Bachelor of Technology | Computer Science West Bengal University of Technology, Kolkata

06/2014

PROJECTS

Promoting ACT (Acceptance and Commitment Therapy) through mobile application

- Conducted user-studies (online survey, interviews, and user feedback) at different stages of the project
- Built low-fidelity and high-fidelity prototype of a mobile application
- Conducted A/B testing
- Conducted Heuristic evaluations as well as collected user feedback on the prototype

Heart Disease Prediction using Data Mining Techniques

In this project, decision tree classifiers as well as a probability-based classifier. The algorithms that were used are Naïve Bayes classifier, J48 algorithm and Random forest classifier. We have taken an existing patient data set of Cleveland from UCI repository to test and analyze the algorithms.